

+33 7 80 04 16 87 e.durand.design@gmail.com

www.emiliedurand.com



About

Interested in both digital and physical products, I have gained experience in both areas throughout my experiences.

Sustainability has also always been at the center of my interests, which led me to co-found a design studio aimed at creating 3D printed objects from recycled biomaterials.

Skills

UX/UI design

User research / Wireframes / Prototypes

Product design

Shape research / 3D modeling / Manual prototyping / 3D printing (FDM)

Web development

CSS / HTML / JavaScript

Languages

Français - Native Anglais - Native

Certificates

Académie Design & Innovation HAIGO, 2021

Computer Science for Business Professionals

Harvard CS50, 2021

Learn How to Code Course

Codecademy, 2020

HTML & CSS Fundamentals

SoloLearn, 2016

Contests

L'Été en rosé

OI Design Awards, 2019 Top 10 (out of 50)

Atelier Amylacé

Les Design français, 2020 Top 3 (out of 10)

SANNY

Wanted Design, 2020 2nd (out of 10)

Education

Training in public policies design

Design Actions Publiques - Île-de-France's Region Counsil February - June 2023

Industrial design diploma

Specialization in product design Strate, School of Design - Sèvres | September - December 2022

I was part of the association Collectif 1.5, which allowed a better link between the school administration and the students

Master in Management - Option E

ESCP - Berlin | September - December 2020

Discovery of the entrepreneurial ecosystem through the creation of a fictitious start-up, FixMeUp: repairing electronic objects.

High school diploma specializing in literature

Institut du Sacré-Coeur - La Ville du Bois | July 2017

Having joined the student association, I was in charge of the creation of posters throughout the year, as well as the photography of events.

Work experience

Product and UX/UI design

extrude.studio - Paris | January 2021 - March 2023

With four other designers, we created custom objects and repaired and improved existing ones, using 3D printing of recycled materials.

UX/UI designer

ValueCo - Paris (remote) | July 2021 - Present

Design of a complete SAS platform in the field of finance, using the Material UI library.

Lead designer UX/UI

Leonessa - Philadelphia (remote) | November 2021 - December 2022

Design of a website and simulation tools for an insurance company. This experience was a great opportunity to understand how freelancing works, how to deal with clients and developers, and how to lead a team.

Designer produit et UX/UI

Plast'if - Paris | March - August 2020

Creation of the catalog of 3D printable objects by the Plast'if machine, design of the application and the interface of the machine, help in communication and contact of customers.